A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Administration, 1995-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
- Series III. Correspondence and supporting documentation: Office of the Secretary, 2004-2009., Extent: 2 cubic feet (6 boxes). (Box 21-26)
  - Budget - Responsibilities Outlined in 2006-2008 Budget, 2004-2006 Budget and Budget Amendments, 2006 July 27. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - Office of the Secretary of Administration, 2009. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - General Services, Dept. of (folder 1 of 2), 2009. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - General Services, Dept. of (folder 2 of 2), 2009. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - Human Resource Management, Dept. of, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - Minority Business Enterprise, Dept. of, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - Employment Dispute Resolution, Dept. of, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - Human Rights Council, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - State Compensation Board, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - State Board of Elections, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Budget Reductions FY2010-2012 - Virginia Public Broadcasting Board, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Comprehensive One Stop Workforce Centers, 2008. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Critical Infrastructure Protection and Resiliency Strategic Plan, 2008. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Federal Stimulus, 2009. (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Federal Stimulus - Database extraction (Category: Infrastructure Broadband), 2009 March 9. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Federal Stimulus - Database extraction (Category: Infrastructure Other), 2009 March 9. (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Federal Stimulus - Database extraction (Category: Unknown), 2009 March 9. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Financial statements, 2006-2007. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Financial statements, 2008. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Financial statements, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Future of Richmond's Past, 2009. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Government Performance Project (folder 1 of 4), 2004. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Government Performance Project (folder 2 of 4), 2004. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Government Performance Project (folder 3 of 4), 2004. (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Government Performance Project (folder 4 of 4), 2004. (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Key Performance Measures and Objectives - SOA agencies, 2007; 2009. (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Norfolk Light Rail, 2008. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Productivity Investment Fund, 2009. (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Productivity Investment Fund - Board meeting materials, 2009 July 23. (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Productivity Investment Fund - Grant submissions, 2007. (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Productivity Investment Fund - Proposals for funding, 2009. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Reconciliation Statue, 2006. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Capitol Foundation - Board meeting, 2007 May 23. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - State Capitol Rededication and Visit of the Queen of England, 2007-2008. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Commission on Immigration, 2007. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Commission on Immigration - Meeting materials, 2008 January 4. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Family Impact Seminars, 2009. (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Performs, 2008. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Sesquicentennial of the American Civil War Commission - Advisory Council, 2007. (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Decision briefs, 2006-2009., Extent: .20 cubic feet (6 folders). (Box 27)
  This series is housed in 1 box and is arranged chronologically. This series consists of copies of decision briefs directed to Governor Timothy Kaine on which the Secretary of Administration was asked for approval related to agencies/issues under the SOA, and original decision briefs directed to the Secretary of Administration. This series documents the Secretary of Administration and Governor's response to requests from agencies for budget appropriations from various funds, for executive orders, for authorization for the purchase or transfer of property, and for approval of agreements or statements.
  The decision briefs to the Governor include a description of the request, the recommendation and signature of the Director of the Dept. of Planning and Budget, Richard D. Brown or the requesting Secretary, the concurrence of the Secretary of Administration and the Secretary of Finance Jody M. Wagner, which can either be to Recommend, Recommend with modification, or Deny, and their signatures, and the approval, approval with modification or denial of the Governor and his signature. The briefs also include background information, a discussion of the issues involved, and legislative citations. These records may also include supporting documentation such as correspondence, reports, and copies of code citations.
  The decision briefs to the Secretary of Administration similarly include a description of the request, the recommendation and signature of the agency head making the request, the approval, approval with modification, or denial of the Secretary and her signature. These briefs also include background information, discussion, conclusion and references, and may include supporting documentation such as correspondence, copies of code citations, and publications. Most of the briefs sent directly to the Secretary of Administration were made in 2009 and the majority of those briefs document requests for exemption from the state printing prohibition.
  - Decision briefs, 2006. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Decision briefs, 2007. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Decision briefs, 2008. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Decision briefs, 2009 January-April. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Decision briefs, 2009 May-August. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Decision briefs, 2009 September-Decemeber. (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Series V. Environmental impact reports, 2006-2009., Extent: 3.35 cubic feet (10 boxes). (Box 28-37)
  This series is housed in 10 boxes and is arranged chronologically by date of approval or disapproval of the memo. This series contains environmental impact reports and studies created by state agencies prior to beginning construction projects. Section 10.1-1188 et seq., of the Code of Virginia requires that any state agency, institution or branch of government proposing to undertake a "major state project" prepare an environmental impact report. A "major state project" is defined as construction of a facility costing $100,000 or more, or the acquisition of land for which construction is contemplated. The Governor's approval of the report is required before any funds are expended. This responsibility has been delegated to the Secretary of Administration pursuant to Executive Order Number 88 (01).
  The report packets include the memorandum of approval (or approval with stipulations or disapproval); comments by the Department of Environmental Quality (DEQ) that include a description of the project, environmental impacts and mitigation, and regulatory and coordination needs; and various other memos and correspondence. The DEQ comments take into consideration the impact on water quality and wetlands, erosion and sediment control and stormwater management, air quality, solid waste and hazardous waste management, natural heritage resources, wildlife resources, historic and archaeological resources, forestry and tree protection, geologic and mineral resources, energy conservation, transportation, the Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act, and local and regional concerns. Other agencies such as local governments, regional planning district commissions, the Department of Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of Historic Resources, Department of Transportation, Department of Game and Inland Fisheries and the Virginia Marine Resources Commission were also consulted and asked to comment on any potential problems.
  The projects range from small renovations and additions, to large scale construction efforts. The majority of the projects took place on university or community college campuses, at state parks, and at Department of Transportation facilities. There are also a significant amount of projects involving the Statewide Agencies Radio System (STARS) Project under the purview of the State Police.
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 January 4. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 January 19. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 January 20-27. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 Feburary. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 March 1-17. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 March 20-29. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 April 3-6. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 April 21-28. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 May 4-19. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 May 22-30. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 June. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 July. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 August. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 September. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 October. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 November. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2006 December. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 January. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 February. (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 March. (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 April. (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 May 7-21. (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 May 23-30. (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 June. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 July. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 August. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 September. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 October. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 November 5-13. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 November 16-28. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2007 December. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 January 14-18. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 January 24-31. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 February. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 March 4-19. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 March 25-28. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 April 3-9. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 April 15-24. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 May 2-16. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 May 16-29. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 June 3-5. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 June 9. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 June 13-18. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 June 20-25. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 June 27. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 July 2-11. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 July 23-28. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 August. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 September. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 October. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 November 3-7. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 November 18-26. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 December 15. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2008 December 19. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 January. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 February. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 March. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 April. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 May. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 June 11-16. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 June 23-30. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 July. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 August. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 September. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 October 1-6. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 October 19-20. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 October 21-29. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 November. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Environmental impact reports, 2009 December. (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Series VI. Intellectual Property Rights, 2008-2009., Extent: .10 cubic feet (2 folders). (Box 37)
  This series is housed in 1 box (2 folders) and is arranged chronologically. This series contains disclosures, correspondence and other supporting documentation for reporting patentable or copyrightable subject matter in accordance with Virginia's Intellectual Properties Policy set forth by Executive Memorandum 4-95. This policy states that any employee of an executive branch agency who invents or produces a potentially marketable or commercially valuable creation, process, device, technique, or method during working hours, within the scope of employment, or when using state-owned or controlled facilities is required to disclose that information. These records also include requests to release intellectual property rights and to license copyrighted material. The disclosure forms contain descriptions of the inventions which include among others an integrated forest service resource information sytem and an application that provides a method for teleworkers to account for their activities. This series only includes records for 2008 and 2009 - records for 2006 and 2007 were not transferred.
  - Intellectual property rights, 2008. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Intellectual property rights, 2009. (Box 37, Folder 6)
- Series VII. Legislative Files, 2006-2010., Extent: 3.25 cubic feet (10 boxes). (Box 38-47)
  This series is housed in 10 boxes and is arranged chronologically and by record type thereunder. This series includes legislative proposals, legislative action summaries, and other miscellaneous legislation-related documents which explain in detail various bills brought before and voted upon by both the Senate and the House of Delegates. These legislative files document General Assembly activity involving the agencies assigned to the Secretary of Administraion and include input from agency heads as to how legislation might effect agency operations. The legislation in this series contains information on a variety of subjects, the most prevalent being health care, voting, and campaign finance.
  Legislative Proposals are provided by individual agencies under the Secretary of Administration and include a statement of need for legislatiion within which ideas and suggestions for agency specific legislation are documented. The proposals also include fiscal and other impacts of the legislation. Legislative Action Summaries include a bill summary and other background information on the legislation and indicate whether or not the Secretary supported the bill, supported the bill with amendment, opposed the bill, or took no position on the bill. Most summaries contain comments and reasons for support or opposition. Also included may be Fiscal Impact Statements that detail the monetary affects that any legislation may have, and Drafting Requests to the Division of Legislative Services for draft legislation.
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 3-HB 37), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 46-HB 89), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 101 and SJ 23; HB 103-HB 185), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 203-HB 281), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 291-HB 311), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 331-HB 369; HB 374 and HJ 41; HB 375-HB 376), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 387-HB 431), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 451-HB 462), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 467-HB 476; HJ 47), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 5-SB 76; SJ 48), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Fiscal impact statements (HB 13, HB 185, HB 203, HB 220), 2006. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Legislative proposals - General, 2007. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Legislative proposals - Compensation Board, 2007. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Legislative proposals - Human Resource Management, Dept. of, 2007. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Drafting requests, 2007. (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2550, HB 3065, SB 697), 2007. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of General Services, 2008. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of Human Resource Management, 2008. (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Legislative proposals - Human Rights Council, 2008. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Legislative proposals - State Board of Elections, 2008. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 6-HB 54), 2008. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 64-HB 99), 2008. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 100-HB 199), 2008. (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 226-HB 297), 2008. (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 301-HB 397), 2008. (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 426-HB 595), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 615-HB 687), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 724-HB 799), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 800-HB 867), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 900-HB 972), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1017-HB 1099), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1124-HB 1197), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1235-HB 1298), 2008. (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1329-HB 1392), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1410-HB 1494), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1536-HB 1577), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action summaries (HJ 56-HJ 166), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 7-SB 38), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 51-SB 82), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 105-SB 199), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 206-SB 292), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 316-SB 358), 2008. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 417-SB 442), 2008. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 447-SB 499), 2008. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 505-SB 595), 2008. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 615-SB 696), 2008. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 705), 2008. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 715-SB 790), 2008. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous legislative material, 2008. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of Employment Dispute Resolution, 2009. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of General Services, 2009. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Legislative proposals - Human Rights Council, 2009. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of Minority Business Enterprise, 2009. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Legislative proposals - State Board of Elections, 2009. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Drafting request forms, 2009. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Bills approved for pre-filing, 2009. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1588-HB 1634), 2009. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1643-HB 1685), 2009. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1712-HB 1749), 2009. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1765-HB 1799), 2009. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1812-HB 1878), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 1881-HB 1996), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2015-HB 2083), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2103-HB 2197), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2219-HB 2388), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2422-HB 2496), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2509-HB 2594), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2608-2628), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (HB 2632-HB 2672), 2009. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 810-848), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 852-SB 883), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 925-SB 998), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 1006-SB 1096), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 1102-SB 1192), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 1203- SB 1277), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 1310-SB 1355), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Legislative action summaries (SB 1365-SB 1539), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Legislative action summaries (SJ 281 ), 2009. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous legislative records, 2009. (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Legislative proposals - General, 2010. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of General Services, 2010. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Legislative proposals - Human Rights Council, 2010. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Legislative proposals - Dept. of Minority Business Enterprise, 2010. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Legislative proposals - Public Broadcasing Board, Virginia, 2010. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Legislative proposals - State Board of Elections, 2010. (Box 47, Folder 6)
- Series VIII. Public Broadcasting Board records, 2006-2009., Extent: .55 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 48-49)
  This series is housed in 2 boxes and is arranged by record type and chronologically thereunder. This series includes correspondence and supporting documentation, board meeting records, applications and contracts which document the activities of the Virginia Public Broadcasting Board. The Public Broadcasting Board is the channel through which public television and radio stations (including the radio reading service) receive state financial support. The board provides grants and contracts to stations that enable them to implement instructional programs and other community interest programming. The majority of the correspondence is related to grants and funding issues, including those related to budget reductions in 2009, and also includes other budget and financial information, grant proposals and grant reports. The board meeting files contain agendas, draft minutes and other related documentation for several board meetings, but they do not include records for all board meetings. This series also includes applications for community service grants for public radio, applications for community service grants for public television, and applications for operating grants for radio reading services, as well as instructional telecommunications services contracts and monthly contract statements of funds expended.